Guide to the Democratic Socialists of America Records TAM.105
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series XII: Unprocessed
  - Records: "Manuscript, New Yorker article (Harrington), 1987; National Political Committee, 1991-92, 1997; Assistant to Director Search, 1991; some international correspondence; Organizing Institute, 1993; National Youth organizer Dinah Leventhal's reports, 1990; various administrative and topical files, 1987-1997 (Box 76)
  - Records: Harrington writings: End of the Left? [1985], American Socialism, shorter writings; writings about MH, including Richard Flacks on Harrington and Tom Hayden; National Executive Committee Minutes 1985; Religion and Socialism Committee (about 1/3 box; Labor Day 1991; Democratic Left, 1978-1991 (Box 77)
  - Records: Youth Section, 1991-92; Campaign for Peace in the Middle East; dsanet, 1995; Democratic Left, 1989-91; DSA Winter Retreat, 1996, 1989-1996 (Box 78)
  - Records: Almost entirely Youth Section; American Student Mobilization; DSA leadership retreat, 1989, a few other DSA anad topical files, including Health Care, 1988-1994 (Box 79)
  - Records: Michael Harrington's death and memorial; one file of Harrington correspondence, 1988; Committees and Commissions, latter 1980s; Budget, 1989; "History--DSA/DSOC" [undated]; Robert Delson correspondence with DSA, 1990., 1985-1990 (Box 80)
  - Records: Harrington Correspondence: receeived, 1988 (includes ltr from Bill Moyers asking him to appear on public television), sent, 1989, "Harrington Current" - speaking engagements, 1988-89; Clips about Harrington, 1982-89; one thick file of Harrington writings; file on Harrington's receipt of Debs-Thomas award, Bulk, 1988-1989 1982-1989; 1988-1989 (Box 81)
  - Records: Articles by and clippings about Harrington; Death of Harrington, clippings and other materials; bibliography of Harrington's writings, 1946-74; Fundraising; some National Office Correspondence, 1990s; DSA constitution, discussions on, 1980s; Education Committee, 1991, 1985-1991 (Box 82)
  - Records: seven videocassettes about "Economic Insecurity"; five audiocassette binders [each holds 12 cassettes]: two Institute for Democratic Socialism conferences, focus is economics and politics; the other three binders are on various policy issues and appear to be tied to Democratic Party Conventions or congresses in the 1980s (Box 83)
  - Records: Financial and Budget, 1987-93; Director Michael Lighty speaking tour, 1992; Convention, 1993; "California State-Wide Org" file; Commissions: Environment, Anti-Racism; file on "Recruitment Video"; Religious Socialism correspondence (one file), 1987-1993 (Box 84)
  - Records: One thick file, Socialist Internatnional correspondence, 1980-81; National Political Committee minutes [binders] 1997-98; Youth Section conferences, 1981-94; clippings on Harrington's death, 1981-1998 (Box 85)
  - Records: all Youth Section, 1987-95, including National Office Collective Minutees, 1993-95; Executive Committee minutes, 1986-90; Keylists, late 1980s; "Chapter Surveys, 1992", topical files, including Middle East, Apartheid, 1987-1995 (Box 86)
  - Records: all Youth Section, 1983-95. Includes, Keylists, conventions and conferences, correspondence, an organizing manual, a proposal to hire a California organizer, reports and political statements, a file on The Activist/Labor Activist, 1983-1995 (Box 87)
  - Records: DSA, including Executive Committee minutes, 1986-88; Harry Britt tour, 1983 (SF City Supervisor); files on speaking events for Manning Marable and Cornell West; Harrington Natioanl tour, 1982; Central America Speakers' Bureau, 1984; NYC DSA, 1979-86, including minutes, Labor Forum, 1991 convention, 1979-1991 (Box 88)
  - Records: DSA conventions, 1995, 1997; leadership retreats, early 1990s; correspondence, including emails; Youth Section, 1993-95: conference, 1994, correspondence, several chapter files, 1990-1997 (Box 89)
  - Records: DSA national conventions, 1993, 1995; Key Lists, 1993 (Box 90)
  - Records: National Political Committee, 1992-98; NPC subcommittees; Convention, 1993; Keylists 1992-93, 1992-1998 (Box 91)
  - Records: National Political Committee and its Steering Committee, 1994-95; Issues of Religious Socialism, 1982-85., 1982-1995 (Box 92)
  - Records: Feminist Commission, 1980-88; "Mission Retreat" 1997; National Politicall Committee, 1997 [incomplete]; committee and topical files, 1990s; Youth Section, 1996, 1980-1997 (Box 93)
  - Records: National Convention, 1995, Labor Committee, 1995; Topical files, 1995; "Old Chapter Info" file, 1993; Religion and Socialism Commission, 1993; Socialist Scholars Conference, 1994-96, 1994-1996 (Box 94)
  - Records: National Political Committee and Steering Committee, 1996-97 [incomplete]; Education Committee, 1993-94 [incomplete]; Billy Bragg, 1992; "Organizational Documents--Constitution and Merger Agreement, 1983; Commissions: Feminist, Riligion and Socialism, ohters, 1990s; Nurses Caucus Newsletter, 1993, 1983, 1992-1997 (Box 95)
  - Records: Periodicals" Not Far Enough, 1982-88 (Feminist Commission), Labor Voice, 1988 (Labor Commission), Our Struggle/Nuestra Lucha, 1988-89 (Latino, Afro-American and Anti-Racism Commissions), Religious Socialism, 1985-86; Local Literature Survey, 1998; National Political Committee, 1995 [incomplete], 1982-1998 (Box 96)
  - Records: about half university chapters, no order, late 1980s; Convention, 1995; National Political Committee 1997 retreat; Think Tank project, 1996; Global Justice Task Force, 1994-95; Budget Committee, 1997, 1987-1997 (Box 97)
  - Records: New American Movement, 1974-80; Socialist Standard, 1987, Organize (DSA Activists), 1986-87, Nuestra Lucha, 1984-85; California local chapter files, 1980s, 1974-1987 (Box 98)
  - Records: Computer Disks. 3.5 inch (>100), some labeled, ca. 1994-ca. 2000 (Box 99)
  - Records: Computer discs, 3.5 inches (>100), 1990s, ca. 1994-ca. 1999 (Box 100)
  - Records: Membership surveys, 1995-98; Health Activists Digest (DSA), Summer 1980s; Democratizing Education (NAM), 1981, 1981-1982, 1995-1998 (Box 101)
  - Records: Surveys and membership renewals, 1995 (Box 102)
  - Records: Membership surveys, 1998; International Committee, one undated file; Youth Secton, minutes, 12/30/83;several issues of The Activist (YS), 1986, 1983-1998 (Box 103)
  - Records: Membership surveys, 1995; Youth Section, several files, 1985-86; Days of Decision, 1981-85, 1981-1995 (Box 104)
  - Records: Videocassettes-- DSA meetings, 1981-2001; also a few talks by Harrington, Barbara Ehrenreich, 1987-2001 (Box 105)
  - Records: Education Commssion, including retreat files, early 1990s; topical files, mostly economy, poverty, labor, containing circulars, reports, etc,; Several issue each of the Plant Closings Bulletin (1981), DSOC, and the Third World Socialist, 1984 (Institute for Democratic Socialism, 1987-1994 (Box 106)
  - Records: Labor Commission, 1983-90; Hispanic Anti-Racism Commission, 1987; aobut half the box are chapter files, 1990s-2004, many from Pennsylvania, also NY and NJ, 1983-2004 (Box 107)
  - Records: Videocassettes of Harrington Talks, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 108)
  - Records: Three scrapbooks: Harrington photos, Justice for All campaign, 1987; Workers Party reports, 1940s; issues of Days of Decision, 1980s; about a dozen audiocassettes, 1980s, probably Harrington talks, 1940-1989 (Box 109)
  - Records: Conventions, 1991, 93, 99; Feminist Commission, 1991-92; National Political Committee, Steering Committee, 1994; Key Lists, 1994; Budget Committee, 1991; Correspondence, 1994 (including Member Correspondence), 1991-1999 (Box 110)
  - Records: Political Committee, 9/97; Convention, 1997; National Office Committee, 1992-93; Housing Task Force, 1989; Organization Manual; Progressive Student Network, 1980s; Topical files containing circulars, reports, etc., 1980s-1997 (Box 111)
  - Records: Political Committee, 1994, 2004, Conventions, 1995-2005; Socialist International, 2001; Computer discs, 3x5, undated, unlabeled, 1994-2005 (Box 112)
  - Records: Videocassettes: Michael Harrington, New Directions, 1980s, 1980-1989 (Box 113)
  - Records: Audio (undated): Billy Bragg, Pete Seeger: Songs of Protest; Letter of Critical Endorsement to the 13th World Youth Festival, 1989; Youth Section: Key Lists, Chapters, Internatioanl Union of Socialist Youth, Young Women's Project; Faculty Mailing, 1993; Anti-War Work, 1991, 1989-1993 (Box 114)
  - Photographs: Washington DC Conference; Reproductive Freedom; Activist Individual; Civil Rights March, Boston; DSA/DSOC Conference, NAM; DSCO Board; Freeze March, New York City; U.S. Foreign Relations Policy; Mike and Barbara; Democratic Agenda; DSOC Convention; DSA/DSOC Local Action; Democracy; Democratic Agenda; Convention; DSA Youth Conference; Palme Reception; FRAMES; Solidarity Day; Eurosocialism; DSA Unity Convention; DSA Unity Convention; March on Washington; Democratic Agenda:; Staff/Office; Wimpy; Convention; File in Graphics/Photo Files; Chicago; Jeffrey D. Gold; 31/7 1/E's Vol. 2; We Are Demo Soc w/A Vision; Art DC Millennium; Michael Harrington Event at Roseland for D.S.A.; Michael Harrington w/celebs; Socialism Past and Future; Michael Harrington; "Tribute Photographs"; "National Board "; "Some scenes from the Youth Section"; International Union of Socialist Youth World Festival, circa 1975-1999 (Box 115)
  - Slides: Demonstrations, Rallies, 1978-1981 (Box 116)
- Archived Website, Nov 26, 2008-ongoing
  The Democratic Socialists of America (DSA) was founded in 1983 as the result of the Merger of the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee, founded in 1973 by Michael Harrington (1928-1989). He led the DSA until his death, and the New American Movement, a New Left organization founded in the early 1970s. DSA is affiliated with the Socialist International. The party's platform calls for reforms that weaken the influence of corporations in politics and give more power to working people. The website contains information on their campaigns and programs, which include student debt alleviation, immigrant rights, and the protection of social programs. The website also contains meeting minutes, chapter information, their publication, Democratic Left, their blog, Talking Union, their scholarship fund, and event listings.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.